babylon.com 2001-12-17

# Babylon.com Privacy Statement

Privacy Statement for Babylon

Babylon.com Ltd. is committed to preserving the privacy of our users. This Privacy Statement explains which information we collect and how we use it.

The Babylon.com website ("Babylon Website") entitles our users to use Babylon software (the "Software"), both on line and after downloading it, as well as to participate in our message board service. To improve our site, we use cookies to save our users' usernames and passwords so our users don't have to re-enter them each time they visit the Babylon forums. We also offer our users the option of receiving Help Desk support and our newsletter. As part of the registration process after downloading the Software or when participating in our message board service, Babylon requests the following information: the user's age range, gender, country, zip code, e-mail address and general interests. The purpose of gathering this information is to help Babylon-Provide better service to our users and aggregate information to third parties interested in usage patterns of different demographic groups. Babylon may share information about users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties; however, we do so only in the aggregate. All users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information on message boards, which are freely available to the public. 

Babylon uses this information to contact our users with information related to our Software and services provided through the Babylon Website ("Services"), to personalize the Services, to help us understand the use of the Services, and to describe the Babylon customer base in generally to prospective users, the media and advertisers. When our customers use the Software and Services, we collect and categorize aggregated data, which remains anonymous. 

Our users can at any time add, remove or revise e-mail addresses and any other information previously provided to Babylon, as well as opt-out of receiving our newsletter by sending email to "[info@babylon.com](mailto:info@babylon.com) ", by visiting Babylon.com and modifying the user's profile, or revising the registration form provided with the downloaded software. 

The Babylon Website contains links to other sites from which the software can be downloaded. Babylon does not share any information provided by our users with these sites. However, Babylon.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Websites. 

We also ask users, at their option, to fill out an online survey to assist us in evaluating the demand for new versions of our Software. This survey asks visitors for contact information (i.e., name and email address), to facilitate notifying interested customers of new products and services offered by Babylon. 

We also have security measures (such as firewall protection on our servers and PC's) in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

Users should also be aware of the following: 

  1. The installation process will install additional software to allow our advertising partner Cydoor Technologies to measure aggregate information such as the number of people who see their ad (reach) and the number of times people see their ad (frequency).  
The Cydoor component uses your Internet connection to deliver fresh ads for display in Babylon Tool. Cydoor has designed the component to take up the minimum bandwidth on your line. It transfers data to and from Cydoor's servers only when your ad cache buffer needs to be refreshed. Cydoor has developed this unique technology to minimize use of this precious resource. Each advert banner on your hard disc is about 11.5K. Cydoor's components remove used banners from your hard drive in order to reduce the total number of banners stored in your PC. To find out more about how cydoor manages the privacy of information in conjunction with serving ads on this site, You can also review Cydoor's Privacy Policy on <http://www.cydoor.com/Cydoor/Company/CompanyPrivacy.htm>. Cydoor is also a licensee of the 'TRUSTe' privacy program;
  2. The details users elect to post during the registration procedure or thereafter become the property of Babylon upon receipt by Babylon;
  3. Settings, technical and other information from your computer, such as your operating system, Babylon version, browser version, connectivity, various communication parameters and other information related to the operation and interaction of the Software ("Parameters") may be collected by Babylon, subject to the provisions set forth herein. Parameters are collected in order to provide you with the Software and Services subject to the provisions hereof;
  4. Babylon gathers information and usage patterns relating to our users' use of the our Software ("Usage Patterns") to better understand how such users, as a group, use the software and the various features thereof, as well as to help Babylon tailor offerings to our users as individuals, and to conduct market research; and Various data, including but not limited to, the Parameters and the Usage Patterns may be used in the aggregate for commercial purposes, including without limitation, for advertising, targeted advertising, marketing, co-registration to other services, promotional or any other activity, all subject to the provisions herein.

Questions about this privacy statement should be directed to [privacy@babylon.com](mailto:privacy@babylon.com) for clarification.
